A Guide to the University of Virginia School of Medicine Reports, 1970-2014
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Series I: School of Medicine Annual Reports and Biennial Reports 1970-1989
  - School of Medicine Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report, Surgery, 1984 July 1 – 1986 June 30 (Box-folder 16:14)
    The report is from the Department of Surgery and includes a planning report for 1988-1998.
  - School of Medicine Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report, Urology, 1984 July 1 – 1986 June 30 (Box-folder 16:15)
    The report is from the Department of Urology.
  - University of Virginia Medical Center Biennial Evaluation and Long-Range Planning Report, 1984-1990, University of Virginia School of Medicine, 1985 January 18 (Box-folder 16:16)
    The report includes accomplishments and shortfalls for the 1982-1984 bienniem.
  - School of Medicine Biennial Evaluation, 1986-1989, and Long-Range Planning Report, 1990-2000, 1990 January 10 (Box-folder 16:17)
    The report includes evaluation for 1986-1989.
- Series II: School of Medicine Proposals, 1977-1982
  These papers are narrowly focused as opposed to the School of Medicine Annual/Biennial Reports. They are more proposals than reports.
  - A Proposal to Establish a Program in Epidemiology and Biostatistics (Pratt Funds), 1977 July 15 (Box-folder 17:1)
    The report was prepared by Jules I. Levine, the director of the division of Health Services Research at the Medical Center. It proposed that a portion of the Pratt funds be used to improve capabilities in the fields of biostatistics and epidemiology.
  - Residency Program in Family Practice Lynchburg, Virginia, 1982 January (Box-folder 17:2)
    The Residency Review Committee for Family Practice approved the program with John H. Danby serving as the Program Director with Virginia Baptist Hospital being the parent hospital.
- Series III: School of Medicine Reports on Minority Affairs, 1984-
  The documents mainly focus on increasing the number of minorities in medical school. One of the reports is university wide in its coverage.
  - School of Medicine Summer Enrichment Program, 1984, Final Report, 1984 August 24 (Box-folder 17:3)
    The report was prepared by Wei Li Fang and Maurice Apprey. The course is a six-week program designed to provide minority students with the opportunity to experience the content, volume, and pace of the medical school curriculum.
  - School of Medicine Summer Enrichment Program, 1985, Final Report, 1985 August 22 (Box-folder 17:4)
    The report was prepared by Wei Li Fang. The course is a program designed to provide minority and disadvantaged students with the opportunity to experience the content, volume, and pace of the medical school curriculum.
  - An Audacious Faith: Report of the Task Force on Afro-African Affairs, University of Virginia, 1987 June (Box-folder 17:5)
    Maurey Apprey from the School of Medicine served on the task force which considered black students, faculty and staff at the University. A letter dated September 28, 1987, from President Robert M. O’Neil is included.
  - Strategies for Increasing Minority Representation in Medicine by Moses K. Woode and Kathleen Bodisch Lynch, Assisting Students Achieve Medical Degrees (ASAMD) Project, 1988 February 25-27 (Box-folder 17:6)
    This paper was presented at the 16th Annual Meeting of the Sixteen Institutions Health Sciences Consortium in Norfolk, Virginia, February 25-27, 1988.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine Assisting Minorities Pursue Medical Education (AMPMED) Program, Supplemental Information for Robert Wood Johnson Foundation Site Visit, 1988 March 25 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine Academic Enrichment Programs for Minority and Disadvantaged Students, 1984-1990, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 17:8)
    Program Director: Moses K. Woode, Program Evaluator: Kathleen B. Lynch, Assistant Dean of Student Affairs: Maurice Apprey.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine Academic Enrichment Programs for Minority and Disadvantaged Students, 1984-1991, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 17:9)
    Assistant Dean for Student Academic Support and Program Director: Moses K. Woode, Program Evaluator: Kathleen B. Lynch, Assistant Dean of Student Affairs: Maurice Apprey.
- Series IV: School of Medicine Self-Study Reports, 1974-2014
  - University of Virginia Self-Study Summary Report, Edited by Elaine M. Hadden, 1974 August 21 (Box-folder 18:1)
    The report is part of the reaccreditation process that is required every ten years by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools. This report covers the entire university with only a part devoted to the School of Medicine.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine Summary of the Findings and Recommendations of the Institutional Self-Study Task Force, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 18:2)
    The Chair of the Steering Committee was Fritz E. Dreifuss. Also included is a Synopsis of Student Opinion.
  - Report of the Survey of the University of Virginia School of Medicine By the Liaison Committee on Medical Education Representing the American Medical Association and the Association of American Medical Colleges, 1982 February 14-16 (Box-folder 18:3)
    The Ad Hoc Survey Team recommended that the School of Medicine continue in full accreditation for a period of ten years and that a report be submitted to the Liaison committee on Medical Education (LCME) in five years to address issues of concern noted in the summary of this report.
  - Report University Self-Study Committee on Research and Externally-Funded Grants and Contracts for 1974-1984 with Recommendations for 1985-1995, 1985 March (Box-folder 18:4)
    The Medicine section was headed by Richard L. Guerrant.
  - University of Virginia Self-Study Reports 1984-1986, Report of The Subcommittee on Professional Programs, Preliminary Draft, 1985 May (Box-folder 18:5)
    The Subcommittee member for the Medical School Benjamin C. Sturgill.
  - Report Self-Study Subcommittee on Graduate Programs, [1985?] (Box-folder 18:6)
    The Subcommittee member for Basic Medical Sciences was Thomas W. Sturgill.
  - University of Virginia Self-Study Reports, 1984-1986, Report of The Committee on the Faculty, Preliminary Draft, 1985 June, 1986 April (Box-folder 18:7)
    The Committee member for the School of Medicine was John S. Davis, IV. The report was sent to Dean Norman J. Knorr, School of Medicine.
  - Inside UVA: “Self-study moves to review phase,” 1985 August 1 (Box-folder 19:1)
  - Report of the University Self-Study Committee on the Faculty, University of Virginia, 1985 October, 1986 April (Box-folder 19:2)
    The Committee member for the School of Medicine was John S. Davis, IV. The report was sent to Norman Knorr, School of Medicine.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine Draft Section of Self-Study Report on Minority Student Recruitment and Retention Efforts, 1985 December (Box-folder 19:3)
    Norman J. Knorr from the School of Medicine is sent the report and asked to review the Draft. This report states that UVa as a “predominately white, southern institution has been trying for several years to achieve genuine heterogeneity by encouraging the admission of minority students, and particularly black students to every school of the University. Partly under the pressure of a 1978 court order, substantial steps have been taken towards meeting this goal and it is the purpose of this section of our report to evaluate our achievements to date.” There are two copies of the draft, one with changes written in.
  - University of Virginia Self-Study Report, 1984-1986, the executive summary of Continuing Education, Institutes, and Other Outreach Activities, 1986 March (Box-folder 19:4)
    A letter from Oscar A. Thorup to William H. Muller discusses the summary that is included.
  - Report of the Reaffirmation Committee Commission on Colleges, Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, University of Virginia, 20-23 April 1986, 1986 April-May (Box-folder 19:5)
    The report is the draft report of the visit of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools to the University. Also included in the folder is a memo from W. H. Muller, Vice-President for Health Affairs at the time, commenting on the draft primarily with the Medical Center in mind.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine, Summary of the Findings and Recommendations of the Institutional Self-Study Task Force, 1991 July 2 (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Report of the University of Virginia School of Medicine, Charlottesville, Virginia, Prepared by an Ad Hoc Survey Team for the Liaison Committee on Medical Education (LCME) representing the Association of American Medical Colleges and the American Medical Association, 1998 October 11-15 (Box-folder 19:7)
    The report is the final report for 1998, and includes a prior accreditation survey and progress reports.
  - LCME guide to the Institutional Self-study, Liaison Committee on Medical Education, 2004 July (Box-folder 19:8)
    For full accreditation surveys scheduled in 2005-2006. University of Virginia School of Medicine Institutional Self Study Re-accreditation 2006.
  - LCME Functions and Structure of a Medical School, Standards for Accreditation of Medical Education Programs, 2004 October 11-15 (Box-folder 19:9)
  - Survey Report Guide for 2005-2006 LCME Site Visits, 2005 June (Box-folder 19:10)
    University of Virginia School of Medicine Institutional Re-accreditation Project 2005-2006. This document was reprinted with permission of the AAMC Secretariat of the LCME, 2005.
  - Guidelines for the Conduct of Accreditation Survey Visits, Liaison Committee on Medical Education 2005-2006,2005 July (Box-folder 19:11)
    University of Virginia School of Medicine Re-accreditation Project 2005-2006. This document was reprinted with permission of the AAMC Secretariat of the LCME, 2005.
  - Rules of Procedure August 2005 edition (Revised February and June 2006), 2006 June (Box-folder 19:12)
  - Background and Instructions for completing the LCME Medical Edcuation Database and Institutional Self-study Summary, [2006] (Box-folder 19:13)
    For LCME full accreditation surveys scheduled in the 2006-2007 academic year.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine LCME Institutional Self Study Summary Report, 2006 October 8-11 (Box-folder 19:14)
  - Medical Education Database Sections I-V, University of Virginia School of Medicine, 2006 October 8-11 (Box-folder 19:15)
    The sections are: I. Institutional Setting, II. Educational Program for the M.D. Degree, III. Medical Students, IV. Faculty, V. Educational Resources.
  - Appendix of Supporting Documents, University of Virginia School of Medicine, 2006 October 8-11 (Box-folder 20:1)
    The sections are: I. Institutional Setting (Appendix), II. Educational Program for the M.D. Degree, (Appendix), III. Medical Students, (Appendix), IV. Faculty, (Appendix), V. Educational Resources, (Appendix).
  - Required Course and Clerkship Forms (Years One through Four), University of Virginia School of Medicine, 2006 October 8-11 (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Medical Student Analysis and Graduation Questionnaire Results University of Virginia School of Medicine for the Liaison Committee on Medical Education, 2006 October 8-11 (Box-folder 20:3)
  - The Role of Students in the Accreditation of Medical Education Programs in the U.S. and Canada, Liaison Committee on Medical Education Committee on the Accreditation of Canadian Medical Schools, 2011 July (Box-folder 20:4)
    Downloaded from LCME website and reprinted, with permission, for use by the University of Virginia School of Medicine, November 2001.
  - University of Virginia School of Medicine LCME Self-Study Summary Report, 2014 October 19-22 (Box-folder 20:5)
  - Required Course and Clerkship forms (Years One through Four) University of Virginia School of Medicine, 2014 October 19-22 (Box-folder 20:6)
  - Medical Student Analysis and Graduation Questionnaire Results for the Liaison Committee on Medical Education, 2014 October 19-22 (Box-folder 21:1)
  - Medical Education Database Sections I-V University of Virginia School of Medicine, 2014 October 19-22 (Box-folder 21:2)
    LCME Data Collection Instrument for Full Accreditation Academic Year 2014-2015; Section I. Institutional Setting, II. Educational Program for the M.D. Degree, III. Medical Students, IV. Faculty, V. Educational Resources.